Everyone welcome to build twenty fifteen hope you're enjoying the conference so far...program
manager on the visual cplus-plus team and welcome to our session on be more productive
with the visual cplus-plus id with tips and tricks so this presentation is going to be
fool of features bs is full of features that are really,
really useful...only...known about them so that's what we're going to do
in today's presentation I want to give you guys a quick overview of
all be going through in the demo so...sort of categories
...that we're going to go through first and foremost is using visual studio without
...project because his entire presentation is useless if you
can't actually get your code inside visual studio to take advantage of the features that
has so I'm going to show you some ways you can do that even if you don't have...as project second is
finding things around the id this category it helps you to recall either
features or parts of your code as you're exploring around where, you know,
it's probably in there but you're just not quite sure the exact location is so these features
...let you quickly usually type stuff and, go exactly find what you...next
...in the pretty sensitive thing amongst developers just going to go through some...
for many features in via stony fifteen that you can take advantage of to personalizing
customize your own code forces refactoring free factoring is a new experience that
is part of us twenty fifteen from previous additions of visual studio going to go
through a couple of neat little tips and tricks that are sort of hidden
you may not have known about at first glance hopefully you'll find is useful as well and finally
...miscellaneous features that we still think are really cool but they don't quite fit into the
other categories so let's get right into the demo so as I mentioned the first set of features that we're
going to go through is about using visual studio without having a visual studio project
because entire presentation is useless if you can't get your code inside visual studio
to take advantage of all the features that we're going to be talking about the first feature that I want to talk about
...single file tells us more accurately it's enabling browsing
...since navigation other id features for
standalone files that aren't part of visual studio projects here...office we
...single file...sense because
the intelligence features comprise major portion of the benefits that you're getting
...usually opening a single file your...so how
...feature works is...go to file explore and basically you'll double-click on
usually a cp or header file you can also do the same thing by going
...visual studio and...file open file?
The features going-to-take some time to process file which includes the other
sources and headers that are in the same directory as the...opened but once the intelligence
coloration cakes in like this that's when usually know that you radio
...you can see I've got reference highlighting here I can write click here perform a
definition it'll open that file for me...back to the cp...
Performance and edits here you can see that I can get member lists I've got the
intel's...quick info...basically getting a lot of the benefits
that an individual studio project without having the project now there's some
limitations the feature first you can't build and run in a single file
and because the feature is only initially
designed to look at your current directory if you have any header files here
...located in places other than your current
directory you won't get intel sense for the symbols there is something you can do to help
intel's so on where you can do is you can open the intelligence...under
cplus-plus advanced and what I'm using right here is a feature called quick launch I
activated with control q I'll be talking about this feature a little later than demo
version type intel's sense it return it'll take me right there so you can find a single file
tells since features under this section of idea of all because of the potential for a lot of
squiggles to...we disable squiggles but you want to turn them on you can see what things
your project dismissing here I'm going to switch to a simple demo to showcases
functionality what I have here
are two directories one contains files pertinent class a what contains files pertinent class
be now what I have open here in visual studio is class
a that cp you can see that...to include class speedup
h but because the only thing inside classy files this class a single file
...doesn't know about class be at this time to demonstrate this you can see that I can get member list
show up for a but I try to do the same thing for be nothing happened?
...it out what I'm going to do is write click and
go to properties and by including class be files in the
include search path I can help the feature find more information to provide...tells...
Very quickly you'll see the...from here if I type in be dot
get the...for class be finally just as a
...confirm whether or not you're in single file intel's and snowed or normal mode usually under the
nav bar you'll see miscellaneous files instead of the normal project and by the way of the
...our functionality works as you'd expect.
For a second topic on using visual studio without of
visual studio project things that build with microsoft build which includes things not built
in visual studio will produce a pb file as long as you
have a pb there's an extension for visual studio that will reverse engineer
visual studio project from the pb so that you can take advantage of visual studio
features like browsing intel's sense and navigation so here I am on the vs gallery page
...pd project you'll see there's a version for twenty thirteen aversion for twenty twelve
envious twenty fifteen goes out we should
have something working for that as well so here in this folder I have to
...that was produced by legacy build system and also gives me a
pb I don't have a project but now...installed pb project
tool let's say we can do with it I'm going to get a file open projects.
And, I open my legacy folder I can see that I can open to
...as a project now this section up here it
...the absolute paths that are contained in the
...because you're directories and your original machine are probably different from the one which
you're trying out pd project in visual studio you have to help the tool find the new path to where files
are located so what I'm going to do is map this folder to my repository
for all my files are once I do that you can see that the tool basically filled in the
blinks I'm going to hit finish ...I'm...the project here.
And, now can open the projects these features like a definition
...advantage of other visual studio features.
Ventura second category futures this is finding things
around the id the first one that I want to talk about is quick lunch default for quick
conscious control q it's going to put your cursor up here in the quick lunch box
quick lunch does...can find any command or feature within visual studio anything that you would
access from clicking on the menu items or sub menu items
...activate from quick launch so,
for example, let me do a...project right now and you'll see the familiar output window some people like the
airlift other people don't fearless is a default window if you don't quite remember
were airlift is under one of these up here you can just go to quick launched type in
...lists
...show it just enter and now you get error list you're going to be seen me use quick
climbs constantly throughout this presentation...hope it'll be apparent how useful of...
The next feature I want to discuss is navigate to the default for this is control
common and what navigate to does is that
it can navigate you to any symbol definition or file in your project?
So, we take a look at my solution explore over here you can see
some my files and case my project is really large and I don't want to use
mouse to figure out where these files are located I can just type it in navigate to.
If I arrow down to different entries
...temporarily open that file and I want to stick with the file I can
...document...wanted to point out some things search capabilities if I only
want to search within member functions of standard class I can typing standard class
...colin and it's only going to show me from that class.
To...this point I have to functions
call do something one-c direct class
...and standard class but if I know I just want to look at the one in...direct classed
...here's how I...last thing that I want to mention about navigate to is this little
feature so the click on the down-arrow here you'll see there's
the search option called show details this is a pretty useful
feature so if I type in standard you'll notice in this area that you
now get a lot more details about each of the things that you're looking at
so make sure to turn on that future as well.
Problem up here I want to make note some customers of asked us if we can make
the option available to resize these nav bar columns.
You can indeed do this
...click can drag and these settings will stick figure next session.
Continue the topic of finding things around the id in your code...to talk a little bit
about member list member list is the auto complete functionality of
intel sense and I want to show you some of the smarts...the future when it comes to
...sub strings and subsets of your search.
...first example...these
...methods in string that are very similar now the thing is that I can type in
tr cmp.
And, I'll get all of those entries and also just by typing
...cmp you can see that it's still not too hard-to-find the entries you
To do...standard
classing and notice that I have some public and private functions a lot of them involved
...a lot of them start with letter f to go back to where with...
frame mouse and trying to figure out which one of these files up here with my previous file
...going to use the navigate backward feature by typing control minus that feature
is located here navigate backward and navigate for this is useful
forget into that place that you just left so if I type in the equals cdot
f it's going to initially show me those relevant functions that return in
...now currently the relevance because there public and they start with
letter f but if I hit controlled jade which is the short-cut for
member list it's now going to show me both public and private functions that
...so basically the first invocation of
member list removes the accessibility filtering if there's anything to remove
ahead again what it's going to do is remove any of the textual
...now things that don't start the letter
f so return something that's relevant and integer including boolean functions shows of
...list to showcase some additional our let's say I wanted to access function that returns
able I can actually this type in ft...ab and I'll show up we're
hoping that we'll be able to extend the smart filtering of number list to navigate to
...other search features as well.
Our file category of funny things
around the id I wanted to draw some attention to the improvements that we made to find files
...files as an augmented version of the usual control f find
feature that you find in pretty much any windows application that has any sort of text...to
...funded files isn't cplus-plus specific but one of the
dave's on our team did work on improving the features so I always like college of
...some other features alongside this I'm going to make the demo in
real-time and show off the find files improvements so
...system what I want to do is declare twenty-seven integer variables
alpha one throughout...nine beta one through baited nine and...one through eight...nine
...to put them in a function called function one and here's what I'm going to do instead of typing and
...alpha one semi call-in and then
copying pacing this and tree more times I'm going to hold
down the all key and the shift key I'm going to hit the down-arrow eight times.
What's happening
inside a cursor is being created at this column for each of those lines and now what I'm going to do is type
...alpha sceptical and, now I can quickly.
Create the beta and...variables I am going to copy this and
...twice I'm going to do the same things edit alpha here polled alton shift.
And, then changes to beta.
...slightly faster I'm just going to hold down the alt key and click drag on the rest of these
...you can notice that the selection sort of extends to whatever and I can just type
in eta now I intentionally highlighted extra line just to show you that it's putting a
...that column selection is happening so do be careful with it
...powerful so now I'm going to showcase the...files feature the
...is control shift f and I'm just going to type in...for now so as expected it
finds all these alpha results the past if you attempted to do a new search
refine results window would remove the previous search results
...search this is a little annoying because sometimes you want to see the results of
to more searches so
we introduce now is on a results option you can click append results and
ava search for beta I will get those results depended in my find results window
the search results are edible so if I was
...find files for eta I'm going to get all the results for
theta as well as I can do is come here and just select everything and...the
...the search results I don't want to see unfortunately there's no way to do
with the lead of your search results...just sat around
...and files again so that I can collapse results if I click on the header the search results and
hit delete or even backspace...delete...results.
Do not...next section formatting every developer out there is unique
...visual and many of you have very distinct ways that you like to format your code
we always add a few more formally...ever release to accommodate different requests
...after watching this section please take some time to reevaluate your settings and see
that's good for the time being to see your formatting needs?
One really cool feature that we have is
...foreman...sometimes you receive some pretty badly rendered code that house
...edit but it's not really a parents we pretty horrible if I did a copy
...into my editor and it still looks exactly like this with other foreman paste
...get all that code formed beautifully
that access the forming options the fastest way to get there is to do control
...for quick launch and type in formatting if you want to make sure you got cplus-plus
...instead of csharp...cplus-plus I want to give you a quick rundown of these
formatting options the general category basically talks about when you want the entered
help you format indentations pretty self-explanatory talks about how you want the entered
into your code spacing a similar about how you want the...space
...code new still specifically with whether to put opening
...and keywords on a new
...each formatting option you'll see a nice little preview of what you can expect
...have that option unchecked or checked then of course there's wrapping
also kind of self-explanatory I wanted to call out a couple of options that we've implemented in
...some customer requests first as you saw earlier when I paste in this code that was
out of...on...however there was a request made to just in
...on paced and not actually format to preserve the position
...embraces and keywords but still and the code you
can find this option under general and the option is...format another one was the
requests not indep name space contents you can find that naturally under indentations.
And, finally there's the requests to not format initialized lists this options under spacing.
And, I copy this example to show you what the issue was
...the option was turned off this the case that you'd run into
...nicely defining this...list of whatever and then when you
proceeded to type in the closing brace would format the code
...thought was extraneous brightspace events...tabs and this is undesirable?
So, the option turned back on now when you type in that
close embrace it stays there just as you expect again each release we put a few more
format options definitely let us know what else you'd like to see.
Four-foot section let's talk about the new refactoring experience and
...twenty fifteen first...I want to talk about is implement...virtual is
...them getting here is the result of having this...derived class
has attempting to inherit from to base constructs but the base constructs have pure
virtual is in them and they haven't yet been implemented in
...class to activate implementer virtual as I can write click on the
classed definition good click actions and...all...virtual is
now right before I do this look over my solution explore and note that while I have something called
...class that age I don't have something called...class of cp good
coding practice mandates that may functions speed for declared and header file
and be defined in a source file of the same name as the header it also involves
appending the override keyword...functions let's...feature does.
If you take a look over solution explore you'd see a...class that...
got created on-the-fly and because changes were made another file
...definition comes up to show you the changes that happen in other file so you don't have to leave your
...context...find...definition to be a theme for refactoring features
...exchanges and other files some you might be familiar with
...definition while we're here you may not know that you can
...definition inside of a big definition so suppose I want to
...definition of...class of sap
definition what happens is that this breadcrumbs trail activates within
...definition and if you hover over little bubbles to tell you
...file you're looking at previously and you can click on them and
the recursive definition can in theory and go on for a while.
Going back to implant commercials just want to
point really quickly that you can activate the feature on just one of the
base classes...just implement pure virtual...that base
...I jumped over to the source file you can see that for each function that has a non
void return type we return a default value so you can immediately...
object and you can build if you want just put it out there we have heard feedback from people who
...preferred that the new functions intentionally break the build by
...an exception for having slash to do in the body we've heard you guys
will see the implementing these options for refactoring features in the meantime if you're
wondering how is able search who've my header my source of quickly I'm hitting control
...control which is toggle header source file you can see it in the right click menu
...feature performs a basic heuristic on a files in the
same directory and looks for its counterpart file the same name...showcase some additional
refactoring features I'm going to remove the newly created functions from the implement
...virtual featured jumping back to my header file you can see that this for declarations
...green schools beneath them if I hover over say this function light bulbs
going to come up...can click on it...going to offer to create the definition of that function
in...class that cp so this is the create declaration definition feature again
...definition comes up because I made changes in other file and itself...me to not have to
switch contexts now suppose I want to do this for all of this functions what
I can do is highlight them...that I don't have to be precise in fact we re
...all the functions in...class know that the constructor
...structure in the function do something already have and implementation going to write click
...actions and say create declaration definition there
are some cases a which this feature can put things into multiple files and we have implemented the
...definition work around for that for the meantime in the output window of
the visual cplus-plus refactoring view you can see exactly what the future did note that
indicate...the functions already existed...double-click on the entry
will take you there and know that the functions have been implemented in order even though
I implemented disposable funk one first...guessed by now one of the themes
for refactoring experience is following good coding practices in this case following good
...practices is preserving the order of functions from
header to the source now the topic of following encoding practices
...that these three functions have been implemented...probably move these the source file
...your team of your kobe mandy different things but just in case you're developer lewinsky
declaration someone place and definitions another you can select the text
right click cyclic actions and...definition location you see those three funders of an
move to the order functions is still preserved
in this case the inline keyword has been added synthesis functions or inline to begin with
...want to delete them I can use my trusty column selection feature
and student in the event that for whatever reason based class one funk
to doesn't belong in...that cp and you want to
...it elsewhere so we think of a light bulb and use the copy signature functionality
...copy...clipboard and then...every...case that function
...retain the benefits of feature and I want to talk about rename refactoring let's say I
wanted to rename see derive classed something else in
...click on any instance of it click and rename and
the rename menu let's just say I wanted to call it c derive class five or maybe
fifty-four because my finger slipped and that I make reference to see derive class
...string here...there's a comment somewhere else my project...make reference to it as well so the preview
...there are categories for symbols?
And, restraints I'm going-to go ahead and accept these changes
for now do a rebuild and you can see that everything's five
now going back into the rename menu I want to discuss this search scope
...right now the scope terms are a little bit...I...to take some time to clarify
them solution and inside current project search for the same things
in your project except that solution looks at every project in your solution and
insight crm project just...your project similarly current project
and global search for similar things...global applies to every
project solution incur project does applies your current project we select one of
these scopes effects the list of files on which rename performs
...search for the symbol that you selected global and current project have
no scope filtering whatsoever so it will include things that are usually
excluded from your project like in your exclude path the other hand solution and
insight current project filter out things and the directory if they're not files that are built
as part of the project we make the default scope solution because
usually you what's-her-name things...your projects you don't want to touch files
...listed in your exclude directories we do plan to clarify these names...the future release and
we have suggestions on the different scopes that we should be looking definitely...for next refactoring
feature point to talk about extract function extract functions a big refactoring feature but it
was a bit tricky to implements we've currently released as an extension obvious gallery so
download the extension install it give...snow you think.
So, my code here I these two segments that are pretty similar such a
probably extracted into its own function to do this right click
slight coke actions and click extract function notice that I
...f in my for the future...extend the selection so
...valid I'm going to hit okay let's call this...matches and there we
go ahead and do a build just to make sure everything's in order and it is?
...the header file you can see that get in matches is declared and header
the reason for this is that the function from which the function was extracted as a member
...standard class...extracts it to the same scope noted...it continues to follow
good coding practice putting get in matches relative to do something.
This is a good time to perhaps plug another feature within the product
features simply called move up move down by like to
call it transpose code let's say I don't like the position of this function,
for example, let's say I want to make a public...can hold on the out key.
And, impress the of aero and notice that it's going to
...code and everything around it and I guess out down the
same thing just in the other action you can be blocks of code the same way.
For...refactoring future we have converter rusting literal
rusting literals are a cplus-plus eleven feature that makes strings particularly those littered with
the scape sequences much easier to read...click anywhere inside a string
good quick actions and...converter...literal how
many back slashes string really have well now you can see unfortunately
there's no convert back to a non raw string...you'll just have to use the and...key.
And, finally allowed to move on to our miscellaneous category staff
miscellaneous section on a talk to you guys about an incredibly useful feature that is
well-documented but pretty hidden macros
and cplus-plus are always a difficult thing for any compiler to deal with
...one that runs our intelligence engine is no difference in the same way like at the beginning
this presentation you can help single file...since give you more accurate results by putting
in a little work you can do the same thing with macros with the construct called a hint file
so what I have here in this file are these two macros define here.
I have the declaration of the function
one here the definition here and a call to it here.
If I write click on this call and
do good declaration it's going to go to the definition instead
...reason it doesn't work is because the macros at the beginning the file hides
the declaration from the tagparser snore to fix this we're
going to do is create a file called cp dot hints at
...this project...going to throw in the to define statements there before I
close visual studio copy these to my clipboard enclose visual studio?
Going to delete the...a file so that intelligence can read parse everything
...click and add a new text documents.
...called the cp...make sure that the type is a hint file and not
...text file...double-click open this up all but it notepad can go ahead
and paste those two defines in save close.
And, now I'm going to open
my project again given moment for the tagparser for intel's
sense to reprocess the solution so now I'm going to write click on this call do
get a declaration and it will correctly find the
...so if you've ever been frustrated with
...declaration not going to the right thing just know that
is usually caused by macro in your file and now, you know, how to help intelligence along
the as a caution don't go crazy with putting every single macro into the file each
...just add the most egregious ones but this process...well-documented
...msdn page and you can...to it at the end of this presentation the second feature
...like talk about is fonts and...this involves being able to edit the default
colors of certain constructs in your code get to the future of course...launched
type inference colors...cplus-plus specific stuff you can find it all here?
If you one of those people who really like seen that magenta on
maroon comments more our to you and if you've ever played with it a little too much I
want-to revert settings just click use defaults.
...change back and finally keyboard shortcuts is
being able to customize short-cut...visual studio
is also a good way to explore what random visual studio features correspond to
your random keyboard combinations or for usefully finding the official name
of feature as its refer to internally in visual studio
...if you have issues with it you can reported to us what's much less ambiguity so we get
to here again I'm going to go to quick...time...let's say,
for example, that I like...so much that I wanted to be activated with control
f instead of the normal find so find out with the features called I
actually come here press control shift f and I see that it's called edit dot
fund files so now I can put that into here and...reassign it I come here typing control
f and...going to show me that's currently being used by edit dot find by can go ahead and
...now when I had control fi get
find files instead of course if you've ever mess things up just a little too much.
Just reset everything's back to normal.
That includes the demo portion of our session right here you'll see all of
the features that we just went through from the categories to the features that
...on the side when I was going through other ones so here's a big overview summary
...what we went through just to make sure you didn't miss anything.
Thanks-again for watching the session you can find some resources here check out the links
on refactoring on hint file of course when our biggest resources is you
guys please feel free to send us feedback questions comments feedback on our
features we'd love to hear from you guys of course the forget to complete evaluation form.